Inventory of the Ginetta Sagan papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Video tapes, 1980-1990 and undated
  - "PRC Forum: David Horowitz,", 1987 (Box 81)
  - "PRC Forum: Milton Friedman,", 1987 (Box 81)
  - "President of Sierra Leone,", 1980 September (Box 81)
    16mm film
  - "Preventing Ethiopian Famine" McNeil/Lehrer News Hour, 1990 March 2 (Box 81)
  - "Southerland/Baez NBC Poland,", undated (Box 81)
    Betacam
- Sound recordings, 1984-1988 and undated
  All on compact sound cassette
  - "Eleanor Roosevelt speech to the General Assembly Plenary, 1948 December 9,", undated copy (Box 81)
  - "Ginetta: Recollections,", undated (Box 81)
  - "GS: Why the Report on Vietnam?,", 1988 June 15 (Box 81)
  - "International Torture in the Eighties" Foreign Exchange, KQED San Francisco, 1984 May 16 (Box 81)
  - "Interview with Former Minister of Justice of Viet Cong,", after 1978 (Box 81)
  - Romaszewski tape, 1987-1988 (Box 81)
    Side A: "Zbigniew Romaszewski's acceptance speech for Aurora Foundation award," 1987 December 3. Side B: "Zofia Romaszewska lists current political prisoners in Poland," 1988 February 5
- Vietnam and Cambodia research materials, 1977 and undated (Box 81)
- Amnesty International, 1985-1986
  - Report to the International Executive Committee, 1985 (Box-folder 82: 1)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and internal documents, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 82: 2)
  - United Nations Convention Against Torture, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 82: 3)
  - Financial records, 1989 (Box-folder 82: 4)
  - GS letter on the 15th anniversary of the end of the Vietnam War, 1990 April 25 (Box-folder 82: 5)
  - Board of Directors annual meeting minutes, 1990 May 8 (Box-folder 82: 6)
  - Pamela Djerassi works of art on paper, 1970, 1974 (Box-folder 82: 7-10)
    Watercolor, pencil, ink, and oil pastels
  - Polish poster slides for Prisoner of Conscience week, 1985 (Box-folder 82: 11)
  - Human rights clippings, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 82: 12)
    Includes some notes
  - Campaign for Women, 1991 (Box-folder 82: 13)
  - Fundraising and correspondence regarding the Convention Against Torture, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 82: 14)
  - Honduras, 1990 (Box-folder 82: 15)
- Vietnam correspondence and printed matter, 1988 and undated (Box-folder 82: 16-18)
- Vietnam correspondence and printed matter, 1977-1991 (Box-folder 83: 1-7)
  Includes GS letter to Michael Posner
- Amnesty International internal documents on military, security, and police transfers, 1983 (Box-folder 83: 8)
- Photograph of GS with Melina Mercouri, early 1970s (Box-folder 84: 1)
- Amnesty International, 1971-1986
  - Board of Directors meeting, 1974 (Box-folder 85: 1)
  - Group 19, 1974 (Box-folder 85: 2)
  - Indonesia, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 85: 3)
  - Advisory board, 1974 (Box-folder 85: 4)
  - Miscellaneous clippings and reports, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 85: 5)
  - Staff meeting minutes, 1974 (Box-folder 85: 6)
  - Model letters, 1974 (Box-folder 85: 7)
  - Morris, Ivan, correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 85: 8)
  - Buckley, William F., correspondence, 1975 (Box-folder 85: 9)
  - Vietnamese students facing deportation, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 85: 10)
  - Medical-scientific committee, 1975 (Box-folder 85: 11)
  - Greece, 1974 (Box-folder 85: 12)
  - Interpol, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 85: 13)
  - Iran, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 85: 14)
  - Iraq, 1975 (Box-folder 85: 15)
  - Notes and correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 85: 16)
  - Greece, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 86: 1)
  - Vietnam, 1976-1982 (Box-folder 86: 2)
  - Internal documents and clippings, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 86: 3)
  - Board of Directors meeting, 1981 (Box-folder 86: 4)
  - Internal documents, correspondence, and printed matter, 1976-1984 (Box-folder 86: 5-7)
  - Prague meeting, 1976 (Box-folder 86: 8)
  - Meeting minutes, 1984 (Box-folder 86: 9)
  - Internal documents, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 86: 10-11)
  - Clippings, notes and printed matter, 1981-1984 and undated (Box-folder 87: 1)
  - Annual general meeting, 1983 (Box-folder 87: 2)
  - Printed matter, 1973-1983 (Box-folder 87: 3)
  - Human rights clippings, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 87: 4)
  - Printed matter, clippings, and correspondence, 1976 (Box-folder 87: 5)
  - Flannery, Christopher, correspondence and report, 1983-1986 and undated (Box-folder 87: 6)
  - Newsletters, correspondence, and internal documents, 1975-1986 (Box-folder 87: 7)
  - 25th anniversary brochure, 1986 (Box-folder 87: 8)
  - Edwards, Don, 1974 (Box-folder 87: 9)
  - Congressional record on foreign assistance, 1973 October (Box-folder 87: 10)
  - Amnesty Action, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 87: 11)
  - Djerassi, Carl, correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 88: 1)
  - Cupertino Courier article on Amnesty International, 1973 January 31 (Box-folder 88: 2)
  - Correspondence and internal documents, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 88: 3-4)
  - Torture in the Eighties, proofs, 1983 (Box-folder 88: 5)
  - Brazil, 1973 (Box-folder 88: 6)
  - Joan Baez's concert tour, 1973 (Box-folder 88: 7)
  - Anagnos, Aris and Carolyn, 1974 (Box-folder 88: 8)
  - Applications, 1974 (Box-folder 88: 9)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box-folder 88: 10)
  - Search committee for executive director, 1974 (Box-folder 88: 11)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 88: 12)
  - State Department letter to Alice Cox regarding political prisoners in Vietnam, 1973 (Box-folder 88: 13)
  - Bay Area Council on Soviet Jewry, 1974 (Box-folder 88: 14)
  - GS letter to the San Francisco Jewish Bulletin, 1974 (Box-folder 88: 15)
  - Jewish inquiries, 1974 (Box-folder 88: 16)
  - GLIDE Memorial Church, 1974 (Box-folder 88: 17)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box-folder 88: 18)
  - Baez, Joan, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 89: 1)
    Clipping, telegram, and script for AI television promotion
  - Korea, 1974 (Box-folder 89: 2)
  - Dolci, Danilo, 1972 (Box-folder 89: 3)
  - Brazil, Chile, and Israel, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 89: 4)
  - Régis Debray letter to Patricia Hearst, 1972 April 12 (Box-folder 89: 5)
  - Business cards received, 1970s (Box-folder 89: 6)
  - New York office correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 89: 7)
  - Special events committee meeting, 1974 (Box-folder 89: 8)
  - Morris, Ivan, 1974 (Box-folder 89: 9)
  - Grunwald, Hanna, 1974 (Box-folder 89: 10)
  - Michaelson, Arthur, 1974 May (Box-folder 89: 11)
  - Sproul, Barbara, 1974 (Box-folder 89: 12)
  - Price, Arnold, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 89: 13)
  - Danto, Arthur, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 89: 14)
  - AI West newspaper, 1973 (Box-folder 89: 15)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 89: 16)
    Includes GS letter to Bob Dylan regarding Victor Jara
  - Expenses, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 89: 17)
  - Foote, Sarah, 1974 (Box-folder 89: 18)
  - McBride, Sean, 1973 (Box-folder 89: 19)
  - Enthoven, Martin, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 89: 20)
  - Fahlander, Inger, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 89: 21)
  - Research department, London, 1973 (Box-folder 89: 22)
  - Executive meetings, London, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 89: 23)
  - Grantham, Mark, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 89: 24)
  - Beirne, Maggie, 1974 May (Box-folder 90: 1)
  - Plant, Roger, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 90: 2)
  - Ennals, Martin, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 90: 3)
  - Fundraising, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 90: 4)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1974
    - Group 2, 1974 February (Box-folder 90: 5)
    - Group 8, 1974 (Box-folder 90: 6)
    - Group 13, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 90: 7)
    - Group 14, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 90: 8)
    - Group 16, 1974 (Box-folder 90: 9)
    - Group 17, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 90: 10)
    - Group 19, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 90: 11-12)
    - Group 30, 1974 (Box-folder 90: 13)
    - Group 38, 1974 (Box-folder 90: 14)
    - Group 42, 1974 (Box-folder 90: 15)
    - Group 72, 1974 (Box-folder 90: 16)
    - Group 84, 1974 (Box-folder 90: 17)
    - Routine alphabetical correspondence, F-G, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 90: 18-20)
    - Routine alphabetical correspondence, H-O, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 91: 1-8)
    - Routine alphabetical correspondence, P-Z, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 92: 1-7)
- Research materials on Vietnam, 1989 and undated (Box-folder 93: 1)
- Matchbox, photocopies, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 93: 2)
- Framed program for a concert benefiting the Ginetta Sagan Fund of Amnesty International, 1996 (Box-folder 93: 3)
- Award, Grand Ufficiali de la Merito de la Republica, 1995 (Box-folder 93: 4)
- Matchbox, 1974-1983 (Box 93)
- Amnesty International posters, 1980s (Box 93)
- Exhibit material for Amnesty International, 1971-1973 (Box 94)
- Exhibit material for Amnesty International, 1974 (Box 95)
- Aurora Foundation memoranda, agendas, and correspondence, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 96: 1-5)
- Biographical clippings, 1966-1990 (Box-folder 96: 6-7)
- Torture research materials, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 96: 8-11)
- Human rights clippings, reports, and printed matter, 1989 (Box-folder 96: 12-14)
- Human rights clippings, reports, and other materials mainly on Czechoslovakia, Vietnam, and the Soviet Union, 1975-1988 (Box-folder 97: 1-7)
- Biographical clippings, 1987 (Box-folder 97: 8)
- Human rights clippings and reports, 1986 (Box-folder 98: 1-6)
- Aurora Foundation and Amnesty International correspondence, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 98: 7-9)
  Includes correspondence regarding GS's car accident in Poland
- Amnesty International, 1973-1988
  - Fundraising proposal to Ross Perot, 1987 (Box-folder 99: 1)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1986 (Box-folder 99: 2-7)
  - Finances, 1988 (Box-folder 99: 8)
  - Western Regional Council internal documents and correspondence, 1987 (Box-folder 99: 9)
  - Fundraising, 1980s (Box-folder 99: 10)
  - Women in prison, 1980-1987 (Box-folder 99: 11)
- Aurora Foundation human rights committee correspondence, 1987 (Box-folder 100: 1)
- Biographical file on GS's accident in Poland, 1987 (Box-folder 100: 2)
- Amnesty International, 1986-1988
  - Children's Rights Now campaign material, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 100: 3)
  - Human Rights Now campaign material, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 100: 4)
  - Conspiracy of Hope campaign material, 1986 (Box-folder 100: 5)
  - Correspondence and reports, 1988 (Box-folder 100: 6)
  - Conference, "Medicine at Risk: The Doctor as Abuser or Victim,", 1987-1988 (Box-folder 100: 7)
- American Association for the Advancement of Science workshop on human rights, 1977 (Box-folder 100: 8)
- Aurora Foundation award for Zbigniew Romaszewski, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 101: 1-4)
  Includes clippings, correspondence, award ceremony program, and acceptance speech by Romaszewski
- Amnesty International file, 1975-1989
  - Czechoslovakia, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 101: 5-6)
  - Gluzman, Semyon, 1975 and undated (Box-folder 101: 7)
  - Ethiopian refugees in Djibouti, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 101: 8)
  - Human rights in China, 1989 (Box-folder 101: 9)
  - Cambodia, 1987 and undated (Box-folder 102: 1)
- Aurora Foundation, 1975-1989
  - GS statement on Indochinese refugees to Congress, 1988 October (Box-folder 102: 2)
  - Vietnam research material, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 102: 3-4)
  - Photograph of GS receiving award from families of Vietnamese prisoners, undated (Box-folder 102: 5)
  - Press releases on Vietnam, 1988 October (Box-folder 102: 6)
  - Report on criminal procedure in Vietnam, 1988 July (Box-folder 102: 7)
  - Vietnam correspondence and research material, 1975-1988 (Box-folder 102: 8-9)
  - Violations of Human Rights in the Socialist Republic of Vietnam, 1975-1988 (Box-folder 103: 1)
    Includes drafts and correspondence
- Amnesty International, 1973-1986
  Contains mainly clippings and press releases
  - Harald Edelstam's statements on Chile, 1974 (Box-folder 103: 2)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box-folder 103: 3)
  - Brazil, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 103: 4)
  - Nicaragua and Guatemala, 1981 (Box-folder 104: 1)
  - El Salvador, 1981 (Box-folder 104: 2)
  - Vietnam, 1979 (Box-folder 104: 3)
  - Terrorism in Iran, 1979 (Box-folder 104: 4)
  - London correspondence, 1973 (Box-folder 104: 5)
  - Kit Bricca correspondence, 1974 (Box-folder 104: 6)
  - Urgent Action reports, 1984 (Box-folder 104: 7)
  - Membership correspondence, 1974 (Box-folder 104: 8)
  - Internal documents, 1984 (Box-folder 104: 9)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box-folder 104: 10)
- Letters of appreciation for Violations of Human Rights in the Socialist Republic of Vietnam, 1983 (Box-folder 104: 11)
- Anne Loftis article on GS, 1979 February 9 (Box-folder 105: 1)
- Printed matter, 1976-1984
  - Human Rights Internet directories, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 105: 2)
  - Amnesty International reports on Zaire, Ethiopia, Argentina, and El Salvador, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 105: 3-4)
  - Guida bilingue alla mostra di strumenti di tortura dal medioevo all'epoca industriale: presentata in varie città italiane nel 1983-84 (Box-folder 105: 5)
    In Italian and English
  - Amnesty International reports on China, torture, the German Democratic Republic, Rhodesia, and South Africa, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 106: 1)
  - Contes d'Afghanistan, by Abdurrahman Pazwak, Jacqueline Verdeaux, and Omar Sherdil, 1981 (Box-folder 106: 2)
  - Cry of the People and Other Poems, by Kim Chi Ha, 1974 (Box-folder 106: 3)
  - Indomptable, by Nguyen Duc Thuan, 1972 (Box-folder 106: 4)
  - Manual on Psychiatry for Dissidents, by Vladimir Bukovskii and Semyon Gluzman, 1977 (Box-folder 106: 5)
- Amnesty International, 1972-1986
  - 25th anniversary fundraising events in San Francisco, 1986 (Box-folder 106: 6)
  - 25th anniversary concert proposal, memoranda, and schedules, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 107: 1-2)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 107: 3-5)
  - International secretariat internal documents, 1984 (Box-folder 107: 6)
  - Mstislav Rostropovich event, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 107: 7)
    Includes photographs of GS and Rostropovich
  - Moran, Rita, 1981 (Box-folder 107: 8)
  - Holland, Agnieszka, 1985 (Box-folder 107: 9)
  - Amnesty Fair fliers, 1973 (Box-folder 107: 10)
  - Internal documents, 1981 (Box-folder 107: 11)
  - Annual general meeting, 1986 (Box-folder 107: 12)
  - Tiziano Terzani articles on Vietnam, 1979 (Box-folder 108: 1)
  - Scientists for Orlov and Scharansky, 1980 (Box-folder 108: 2)
  - Soviet prisoners of conscience, 1980 (Box-folder 108: 3)
  - Sakharov, Andrei, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 108: 4)
  - Orlov, Yuri, 1978 (Box-folder 108: 5)
  - Bukovskii, Vladimir, 1975 (Box-folder 108: 6)
  - Meiman, N., 1978 (Box-folder 108: 7)
  - Free Wallenberg Committee, 1980 (Box-folder 108: 8)
  - Internal documents, 1985 (Box-folder 108: 9)
  - Galinas, Andre, 1980 (Box-folder 108: 10)
  - Center for International Policy correspondence, 1979 (Box-folder 108: 11)
  - SPEAHRhead: Bulletin for the Society for the Protection of East Asians' Human Rights, 1979 (Box-folder 108: 12)
  - Mother Jones, 1980 (Box-folder 108: 13)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box-folder 108: 14)
  - Press kit, 1986 (Box-folder 108: 15)
  - Correspondence and internal documents, 1984 (Box-folder 108: 16)
  - Internal documents, 1985 (Box-folder 108: 17)
  - Collected articles and clippings, 1978 (Box-folder 109: 1)
  - Boudarel, George, 1979 (Box-folder 109: 2)
  - Bustad, Leo, 1981 (Box-folder 109: 3)
  - Cherne, Leo, 1982 (Box-folder 109: 4)
  - Chomsky, Noam, 1979 (Box-folder 109: 5)
  - Denney, Stephen, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 109: 6)
  - Hawk, David, 1983 (Box-folder 109: 7)
  - Jacquenay, Theodore and Victoria, 1979 (Box-folder 109: 8)
  - Lewis, Flora, undated (Box-folder 109: 9)
  - Lynch, Emmett, undated (Box-folder 109: 10)
  - Marotta, George, 1982 (Box-folder 109: 11)
  - McCarthy, Colman, 1979 (Box-folder 109: 12)
  - Northern Ireland, 1981 (Box-folder 109: 13)
  - Press releases, 1978 (Box-folder 109: 14)
  - International Herald Tribune clippings, 1987-1982 (Box-folder 109: 15)
  - Matchbox, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 110: 1)
  - Amnesty Action, 1981 (Box-folder 110: 2)
  - Prisoner of conscience reports, 1979 (Box-folder 110: 3)
  - Reports, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 110: 4)
  - Budgets, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 110: 5)
  - Death penalty, 1980 (Box-folder 110: 6)
  - Menil, Dominique de, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 110: 7)
  - Laras Fund, 1974 (Box-folder 111: 1)
  - Cuba, 1979 (Box-folder 111: 2)
  - Torture and the medical profession, 1978 (Box-folder 111: 3)
  - Turkey and Iraq, 1979 (Box-folder 111: 4)
  - Chile, 1979 (Box-folder 111: 5)
  - Urgent Action reports, 1979 (Box-folder 111: 6)
  - Publicity and promotion for the 20th anniversary, 1981 (Box-folder 111: 7)
  - Statute of Amnesty International, undated (Box-folder 111: 8)
  - Trade and aid, 1980 (Box-folder 111: 9)
- Personal letters received, 1982 (Box-folder 111: 10)
- Vietnam correspondence, research materials, and notebook, 1973-1987 (Box-folder 112: 1-6)
- Biographical clippings, 1986 (Box-folder 112: 7-8)
- Personal correspondence, 1986 (Box-folder 112: 9-11)
- Amnesty International, 1976-1987
  - Notes by GS, 1980s (Box-folder 113: 1)
  - Matchbox, 1980 (Box-folder 113: 2)
  - Amnesty International internal documents, 1979 (Box-folder 113: 3)
  - Afghanistan clippings, 1980 (Box-folder 113: 4)
  - Human rights clippings, 1970-1987 (Box-folder 114: 1)
  - Pakistan clippings, 1980s (Box-folder 114: 2)
  - Collected articles on torture, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 114: 3)
  - Internal documents, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 114: 4)
  - Argentina conference, 1978 (Box-folder 114: 5)
    Includes photograph of male torture victim
  - Medical Advisory Board meeting, 1977 (Box-folder 114: 6)
  - Argentina and Czechoslovakia prisoner cases, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 114: 7)
- GS's notes and writings on human rights, Vietnam, and Amnesty International, 1980s-1990s (Box 115)
- Vietnamese newspapers, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 116: 1)
- Amnesty International, 1978-1984
  - Notes, correspondence, and internal documents, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 116: 2)
  - Guatemala, 1981 (Box-folder 116: 3)
  - Zimbabwe, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 116: 4)
  - Press coverage, 1984 (Box-folder 116: 5)
  - Vietnam, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 116: 6)
  - Correspondence and reports from Physicians Against Torture, 1976 (Box-folder 116: 7)
  - Afghanistan, 1984 (Box-folder 117: 1)
  - Chile, 1973, 1984
    - Berwart, Pablo Alfredo, 1984 (Box-folder 117: 2)
    - Press release, 1973 (Box-folder 117: 3)
  - Cambodia, 1984 (Box-folder 117: 4)
  - Central America, 1984 (Box-folder 117: 5)
  - Guatemala, 1981 (Box-folder 117: 6)
  - Laos, 1980 (Box-folder 117: 7)
  - Middle East, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 117: 8)
  - Philippines, 1981 (Box-folder 117: 9)
- Vietnam research materials, 1985-1986, undated
  - List of camps, 1985 (Box-folder 117: 10)
  - Correspondence and notes, 1985 (Box-folder 117: 11)
  - Doan Van Toai correspondence, 1986 (Box-folder 117: 12)
  - Untitled article by GS, 1980s (Box-folder 117: 13)
  - Le Hoang Minh prisoner questionnaire, 1985 (Box-folder 117: 14)
- Correspondence on women in the Italian resistance, 1986 (Box-folder 117: 15)
- Human rights clippings, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 117: 16)
- GS notes on World War II, 1985 December (Box-folder 117: 17)
- Correspondence and clippings, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 117: 18)
  Includes letters from Arialdo Banfi and Michael Rhodes Films
- Amnesty International, 1974-1987
  Contains reports, clippings, correspondence, and internal documents
  - Argentina, 1979-1984 (Box-folder 118: 1)
  - Afghanistan, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 118: 2)
  - Chile, 1974-1985 (Box-folder 118: 3)
  - Costa Rica, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 118: 4)
  - Cuba, 1984, undated (Box-folder 118: 5)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1982-1983, undated (Box-folder 118: 6-7)
    Includes files on Karel Kyncyl and Frantiek Lizna
  - East Timor, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 118: 8)
  - El Salvador, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 118: 9)
  - East Germany, 1980s (Box-folder 119: 1)
  - Carlos Armando Vargas Lopez, 1982 (Box-folder 119: 2)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1979-1984 (Box-folder 119: 3-4)
    Files on Jirí Wolf and Rudolf Battek
  - Human Rights Now! campaign, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 119: 5)
  - East Timor, 1985 (Box-folder 119: 6)
  - Egypt, 1984 (Box-folder 119: 7)
  - Ethiopia, 1978 (Box-folder 119: 8)
  - Gabon, 1984 (Box-folder 119: 9)
  - Greece, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 119: 10)
  - Guatemala, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 119: 11-14)
  - Guinea, 1982 (Box-folder 119: 15)
  - Haiti, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 120: 1)
  - Iran, 1984 (Box-folder 120: 2)
  - Italy, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 120: 3)
  - Jackson, Karl D., 1981 (Box-folder 120: 4)
  - Lefever, Ernest, 1981 (Box-folder 120: 5)
  - Lilienthal, Sally, undated (Box-folder 120: 6)
  - Maxey, Margaret, 1981 (Box-folder 120: 7)
  - McCloskey, Paul N., 1981 (Box-folder 120: 8)
  - McGee, Vinnie, 1981 (Box-folder 120: 9)
  - Medical Mission Sisters, undated (Box-folder 120: 10)
  - Menuhin, Yehudi, 1980 (Box-folder 120: 11)
  - Messinger, Eli C., 1980 (Box-folder 120: 12)
  - Method of sending letters to CSSR, undated (Box-folder 120: 13)
  - Mission Hospital, 1981 (Box-folder 120: 14)
  - Morris, Edward A., 1980-1981 (Box-folder 120: 15)
  - Mushrooms, undated (Box-folder 120: 16-17)
  - National Academy of Science, 1978 (Box-folder 120: 18)
  - Nuclear matters, 1981 (Box-folder 120: 19)
  - Panzini, Tiberio, 1945 (Box-folder 120: 20)
    Photocopy of letter translated from Italian to English
  - Resistance, 1981 (Box-folder 120: 21)
  - Rostropovich, Mstislav, 1981 (Box-folder 120: 22)
  - Sakharov, Andrei, 1981 (Box-folder 120: 23)
  - Saldiche, Anne, 1981 (Box-folder 120: 24)
  - Salem and Associates, 1981 (Box-folder 120: 25)
  - Sirhan Sirhan, 1981 (Box-folder 120: 26)
  - Social Democrats USA, 1981 (Box-folder 120: 27)
  - Starr, Kevin, 1981 (Box-folder 120: 28)
  - Timerman, Jacobo, 1981 (Box-folder 120: 29)
  - Timor (East), 1981 (Box-folder 120: 30)
  - Turnbull, Wendy, undated (Box-folder 120: 31)
  - Two Steps In, 1979 (Box-folder 120: 32)
  - United States foreign policy, 1981 (Box-folder 120: 33)
  - United States Senate, 1980 (Box-folder 120: 34)
  - Helsinki Watch Committee, 1981 (Box-folder 120: 35)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box-folder 121: 1)
  - Internal documents, notes and correspondence, 1976 (Box-folder 121: 2)
  - Medical committee, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 121: 3)
  - Anti-Defamation League, 1981 January (Box-folder 121: 4)
  - Anti-semitism, 1981 (Box-folder 121: 5)
  - Babu, Abdul Rahman Mohamed, undated (Box-folder 121: 6)
  - Baez, Joan, 1976-1982 (Box-folder 121: 7)
  - Bay Area Council on Soviet Jewry, 1981 (Box-folder 121: 8)
  - Bukovskii, Vladimir, undated (Box-folder 121: 9)
  - California-Nevada Annual Conference of the United Methodist Church, 1981 (Box-folder 121: 10)
  - Cherne, Leo, 1981 (Box-folder 121: 11)
  - Copland, Henry, 1980 (Box-folder 121: 12)
  - Cox, Amy Louise, undated (Box-folder 121: 13)
  - Davies, Louise M., 1981 (Box-folder 121: 14)
  - Day, Dorothy, 1980 (Box-folder 121: 15)
  - Disappearances, 1981 (Box-folder 121: 16)
  - Electrical Power Research Institute, 1981 (Box-folder 121: 17)
  - Equal Rights Advocates, 1980 (Box-folder 121: 18)
  - Execution by left regimes, 1981 (Box-folder 121: 19)
  - Falicoff, Alberto Samuel, undated (Box-folder 121: 20)
  - Freedom House, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 121: 21)
  - Gluzman, Semyon, 1975 (Box-folder 121: 22)
  - Guatemala, 1984 (Box-folder 121: 23)
  - Haig, Alexander, 1981 (Box-folder 121: 24)
  - Hayden, Tom and Jane Fonda, 1981 (Box-folder 121: 25)
  - Healey, Jack, 1981 (Box-folder 121: 26)
  - Helsinki Watch Committee, 1981 (Box-folder 121: 27)
  - Hollister, Charles, 1981 (Box-folder 121: 28)
  - Holocaust Library and Research Center of San Francisco, 1981 (Box-folder 121: 29)
  - Hostages, undated (Box-folder 121: 30)
  - Ideas for projects, 1979 (Box-folder 121: 31)
  - Immigration and refugee issues, 1981 (Box-folder 121: 32)
  - International Conference on the Holocaust and Genocide, 1982 (Box-folder 121: 33)
  - Kirkpatrick, James, 1979 (Box-folder 122: 1)
  - Newsletters, 1972 (Box-folder 122: 2)
  - Printed matter, 1978 (Box-folder 122: 3-4)
  - "Medical Ethics and Torture," by Leonard Sagan, 1976 (Box-folder 122: 5)
  - Clippings and correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 122: 6)
  - Notebook, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 122: 7)
  - Correspondence, clippings, and reports, 1979-1984 (Box-folder 122: 8)